DAMIAN HOWARD

Saint Helens OR ♦ 971-456-2595 ♦ damian.howard1998@yahoo.com

WEBSITE & PORTFOLIO

https://dhoward.pages.dev/

inhttps://www.linkedin.com/in/damian-howard/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Ambitious web developer who enjoys creating sound user experiences and visually appealing interfaces. Approaches each design and maintenance task with deep respect for web development standards and meticulous attention to technical detail. Always willing to learn unknown topics, keep up to date with new best practices or company standards and apply myself to whatever problems you throw at me.

SKILLS

- TypeScript , React JS
- HTML5, CSS3
- Python, C++, C#
- SQL, Firebase

- Agile Scrum Methodology
- Command Line
- Github
- Photoshop

WORK HISTORY

PSE Clerk - United States Postal Service - Scappoose, OR 01/2024 - Current Opened the store each morning without supervision and enhanced customer satisfaction by efficiently sorting, routing, and distributing 1000's of pieces of mail to appropriate P.O. boxes and route stations within the post office each day.

Network Technician II & III - **Zayo** - Denver, CO (Remote) 10/2021-12/2022 Improved network reliability for fortune 500 companies by diagnosing, repairing, and analyzing problems within the Zayo network. Repaired IP and fiber issues on the fly daily in a fast paced work environment using RFC, OTDR, and loop testing. Worked directly with customers and technicians in a remote ticket environment.

Network Analyst - GTT - Denver, CO (Remote) 11/2020 - 10/2021 Received inbound calls from customers reporting issues within GTT network.

Resolved various connectivity issues for end-users through layer 1 troubleshooting or escalating the issue for outages and equipment failures.

Student Assistant Manager - University of CO. - Boulder, CO 07/2018- 04/2020 Scheduled, monitored, and performed troubleshooting for recorded lectures all over campus for the Office of Information Technology at the University of Colorado Boulder, which I was attending at the time. Trained the other student assistants and managed their schedules. Performed hardware and software installations and completed coding projects.

EDUCATION

University of Colorado Boulder B.S. Technology, Arts & Media 05/2020